[engine starts]
[revving]
[upbeat music playing]
[Jerry] What if, at just the right time,
just the right people
made just the right thing?
What if it came out so right
that no matter how hard anybody tried,
they couldn't quite make a thing
that was better than that thing?
It doesn't happen much.
But the 1973 Porsche 911 Carrera RS...
is one of those things.
It was the first time a car company
put a race car into production.
Altogether, they made 1580 examples.
They had thinner glass, thinner metal.
The very first aerodynamic spoiler
ever put on any car sold to the public.
[engine revving]
It has a 210-horsepower flat-six engine.
And all of these numbers mean nothing.
You can ask anybody
that's ever driven one.
There's something about this car
that feels perfect.
[phone ringing]
-[Seth] Hello?
-[Jerry] Seth Meyers?
-[Seth] Jerry Seinfeld?
-[Jerry] That's correct.
We had talked about having some coffee.
What do you think?
[Seth] I would never say no
to coffee with you.
[Jerry] That is what I like to hear.
Hi, I'm Jerry Seinfeld,
and this is
Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
Today, my guest is the beloved host of
"Weekend Update" on Saturday Night Live,
and the new host of
Late Night with Seth Meyers...
Seth Meyers.
[jazz music playing]
Nice to see you.
I'm excited for the reveal
of what kind of car we're driving.
Well, it's a dead-guy car.
I bought it from a dead guy,
and it's not getting sold again
until I'm dead.
This car doesn't change hands
without somebody dying.
-Why did I pick this car for you?
-Why?
-This car is no-nonsense.
-Perfect.
[Jerry] So, you, Adam Sandler,
and Sarah Silverman
are all from the same part
of New Hampshire?
[Seth] Yeah.
[Jerry] Seth, Sarah, and Sandler,
same area.
[Seth] It's insane.
When I was in high school, that was when
Sandler first started coming up.
I remember thinking, "I can't believe
a guy from my town is on SNL."
And then when I was in college,
Sarah was on, and I was like,
"I can't believe two people..."
At that point you think,
"There are not gonna be three."
If I said something funny at school
that got a laugh,
I would come home
and say someone else had said it.
So I didn't feel, um, self-aggrandizing.
Oh, my God.
Because if I told them that I had said it,
they might have just, like,
polite laughed 'cause I'm their son.
Boy, you were really calculating
from the very beginning.
My dad has long said,
"Never say a joke twice
in my conversation."
Because sometimes you'll think
you'll say something funny
and you'll think no one heard it
so you'll say it again.
He's like, "Never do that,
'cause there's a chance everyone heard it
and they didn't like it the first time."
And nothing's worse than saying something
that's not funny twice.
I love how your dad, the finance guy,
has all these comedy principles.
Oh, my God.
So many more than I have.
[jazz music playing]
-[Jerry] So, what year were you born?
-[Seth] '73.
-[Jerry] And this car is a '73.
-[Seth] That's pretty exciting.
[Jerry] When I told you it was a '73,
-it didn't... Wow.
-[Seth] Nothing.
[Jerry] That is really
a special kind of "out of it."
[Seth laughs]
[Seth] That ever appeal to you,
motorcycles?
[Jerry] Yes.
That's like the cigarette
of transportation for me.
The downside far outweighs
whatever upside.
-How many cars do you have?
-An amount that,
if you looked at it, you would not go,
"Well, that makes sense."
I get that.
[Seth] The summer stresses me out.
Because everybody gets so excited
about the summer
and I kind of just don't get it.
People are like,
"How can you be inside all day?"
Whereas I wanna say like,
"Everything I wanna do is inside."
[Jerry] If you give someone a 50,
it's a big thing now,
-where they check it quite a bit.
-Yeah.
And it's like,
"Well, I used it. Why can't you use it?"
We're all just kind of going along
with this "paper has value" scam.
-Right?
-Yes.
So, why don't we just go along with it?
Why are you stopping me?
[Seth] We were doing this show
at the Chicago Improv Festival.
And so that's how SNL first saw me.
Tell me about that phone call.
Somebody I knew said,
"SNL called and they want you to send them
an audition tape."
I remember being incredibly flattered,
but thinking that that would be
the end of the anecdote.
Always thought
the end of the anecdote would be,
"And that was the day
SNL gave me their address."
-[Jerry] How many years you been there?
-[Seth] Just finished my 12th season.
-[Jerry] Holy cow.
-[Seth] I know.
There have been a few people on the show
that Lorne has let me tell we're hiring.
-Taran Killam, who's a cast member.
-[Jerry] Yeah.
[Seth] I was flying to LA.,
and Taran was on my flight.
I was in business class
and he was in coach.
And I walked back and I told him,
I'm like, "Just five years.
All you gotta do is wait five years,
and you'll be in business class."
-Except that's not really true either.
-It's not true at all.
[jazz music playing]
I don't really wanna leave my car here.
I don't like this spot,
in front of this pickup with a bullet hole
-in the windshield.
-[Seth laughs]
It'll be watched over by this
skull-faced woman on the horse.
[Jerry] Know how unhappy
this makes a guy like me?
I'm delighted to see it firsthand.
[no audible dialogue]
-[Jerry] That seem low?
-[Seth] Shouldn't touch the ground. Right?
-Now, I'm not a car guy.
-But even you...
-I would love a coffee.
-I would love a coffee, yes.
-[waitress] Americano?
-Americano's perfect.
I'll try the French press.
We crossed paths at SNL,
when you came to do "Really!?!"
-Right? That was--
-Yeah.
Which was the most fun thing
I've ever done on that show.
The story has revealed many details
about Massa's behavior
and brings us to a segment we like to call
"Really!?! With Seth and Jerry."
[applause and cheering]
I remember being on the phone
with you and pitching,
"Do you think
you'd wanna do a 'Really!?!'"
Remember what you said?
Yeah, I said, "I think I can.
In fact, I think I invented it."
And, Eric, when you finally admitted
you groped a male staffer,
you insisted it was
just during a tickle fight.
Really?
[laughter]
I've always heard that
the political matrix of that show
is extremely difficult to navigate.
Politically, I'm at the top of the show,
so maybe that's why
I think it's not that political.
The way the president is like,
"No, I think this is about
as well as it could run."
[jazz music playing]
How often do you
have to do charity events?
Let me explain to you something
about charity events.
There are people that would say
that your whole career
is an act of charity.
That you devote yourself
to this somewhat painful existence
to make the world a little brighter.
The first time my friends
see me do stand-up,
they all talk about how nervous they are.
When they actually see how minimal it is.
It's like, "He's gonna talk for an hour."
And once they've told me that, now,
that's what I think every time I walk out.
Like, that's my last thought is,
I'm like, "An hour."
It's like that thing I'll remember
at the last minute,
-how far the jump is.
-Mm-hmm.
It's kind of like, "What if I'm at Macy's
and I get diarrhea, what will I do?"
-Right.
-You find that doesn't happen that often.
-You shouldn't plan your life around it.
-No, exactly.
You shouldn't go through your life
wearing an adult diaper, just in case...
you get diarrhea at Macy's.
So you'll take some jokes
from Update, or...
I close with jokes we've cut from Update
because of NBC censors.
-But they're just killers.
-As Rodney Dangerfield used to say to me,
"The killers are wanted in all 50 states."
I met Don Rickles for the first time.
He was sitting at a table alone.
And I was like,
"I love him. I gotta say hi."
-Right.
-So I knelt down and I was like,
"Mr. Rickles, my name is Seth Meyers,
I'm a huge fan."
He was drinking coffee, he looked at me,
rolled his eyes,
took a sip of his coffee...
and then said,
"You're gonna have to give me a second,
I'm not usually this excited
to meet someone."
He said, uh, "I'm sorry to hear
Saturday Night Live got canceled."
And I go, "It didn't get canceled."
He goes, "A guy can dream."
[jazz music playing]
-Did you see Liberace on Sunday night?
-Yeah.
Did you see that thing,
that he sold out Radio City 56 nights?
Fred Armisen from our show
was an usher at Radio City
Music Hall for those 50 shows.
How crazy is that?
But the thing he told me is that
the first night, Liberace was like,
"There's a couple here
who have been married 50 years.
They met at a show of mine."
Oh, no, I know what's coming.
Did it every night. Place would go crazy.
But that is that experience of happiness.
-Like, why not? Everybody's--
-Where's the victim?
-Yeah.
Like, it's all... not true.
There are people who think
that was a rip-off
but I think that's just
the most wonderful part of the experience.
[jazz music playing]
-My dad is a great storyteller.
-What does he do?
-He's just in finance.
-A funny guy in finance.
My mom... Like, when he's trying to tell
a story, like, her interjections...
And the amount I've seen my dad
do this, like...
It's like Kobe Bryant threads
a bounce pass to a lesser player.
-Yeah.
-Just bounces...
He's just constantly like...
Like, "I'm better, I'm better than this."
And they are desperately in love
with one another,
but yet she cannot help but interrupt him.
It would be like if somebody
loved, loved violin
and while the violinist was playing,
kept walking and going,
"How great is this?"
It's the best.
[saxophone playing]
My first four years
on the show were rocky.
Like, "I might be, of everybody here,
the worst one at it.
I might be the worst at impressions,
I might be the worst at accents.
Maybe I should
just be a writer on the show.
Maybe I just don't belong in this cast."
I remember at my third year, my dad said,
"I feel like what you need
to really break out
is, like, a couple more characters."
And I remember saying to him, like,
"You've done a very good job of being
a tough, honest critic with me.
I no longer need it.
So you have to shift
from what you've been doing
to a completely different
role of support."
A great thing my mom used to do
when I started on the show,
was she made a highlight reel
of my time on the show.
But if I had one line
in a scene as a waiter,
she'd just cut that out.
People would come over and she'd go,
"Have you seen Seth on SNL?"
It would jump-cut to me being, like,
"Here, your dinner,"
then it would cut out.
It'd be me dressed in a bear suit,
then it would cut out of that.
I was like, "I think this is less of
a highlight reel,
this is more like a receipt."
[melodious music playing]
My girlfriend and I
got an Italian greyhound.
-These little dogs.
-Oh, yeah, I know those.
I grew up with Old English sheepdogs,
Great Pyrenees.
Like, big, outdoor New Hampshire dogs.
And now I've turned into a guy
who walks a dog who has to wear a sweater.
I always feel like, before you get a dog,
someone should take a pyramid of Alpo cans
and a pyramid of dog [bleep]
and put the dog in the middle.
Now, what we're gonna do is,
you're gonna buy all this
-and turn it into this.
-Right.
-Do you still wanna do this? Yeah.
We feed it, like, the best dog food.
There are times where I'm like,
"Listen, I would eat this."
Only two things would have to
go wrong in my day.
-You got the greyhound as a puppy?
-Yeah.
You know, they have rescues with those,
'cause of the racing and all that.
We didn't do that.
We did everything wrong.
The day we bought it,
we ran into Martha Stewart.
Like, "Where did you get it?"
-Oh, God.
-Immediately.
And I just lied to her face.
Said, "We got it from a breeder."
She was like, "Where?"
I was like, "Missouri."
I was trying to think,
"What is the state...
Martha Stewart is least likely
to know dog breeders?"
Missouri.
[jazz music playing]
So, what will you miss most about SNL?
I wrote a lot of stuff that we filmed,
like the Digital Shorts.
By the way, the digital part
of a digital short,
is this supposed to be some technology
that is not accessible to the rest of us?
Digital? Hold on a second.
I'm still shooting eight millimeter here.
[Seth] So how new are the tires
on a car this age?
[Jerry] You don't go by mileage
with tires, you go by age.
-But how often do you change them?
-Uh, every five years.
-And how long have you owned this car?
-Uh, about five years.
See, it's got quite a bit of power
and it's really light.
[engine revving]
-That make you nervous?
-A little, yeah.
[peppy music playing]
[Jerry] Someone told me
a story the other day.
They were driving in the city...
and there was this car
just driving completely crazy.
Just swooping across like three lanes,
and then back, and then just making turns.
The guy was like,
"What is going on with this person?"
So he pulls up alongside at a light
and it's a middle-aged Asian woman.
And he says to her, "What are you doing?"
And she goes, "I don't know."
[laughing]
She just told him the truth.
The truth ends every conversation.
[Seth continues laughing]
Know what? I didn't bring any money.
I left the money in the car.
-Do you have any money?
-Yeah.
-[waiter] Check.
-Thank you.
I apologize for the...
Oh, yeah, no, you seem broken up.
Thank you. Why am I thanking you?
I bought you lunch.
[Jerry] How much tip did you...
-I wanna...
-A good one.
-Show business good?
-It was show business good.
Okay.